A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Staff Subject Files, Bonnie Jenkins FA1847
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Staff Subject Files, Bonnie Jenkins
1983-2007
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
Jenkins, Bonnie
FA1847
0.76 Cubic Feet 3 boxes (1 letter document box and 2 half letter document boxes)
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged in one series:
1. Ford Foundation Reports on Foreign Policy Ford Foundation Reports on Foreign Policy, 1983-2007
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to RAC in 2019 and 2020 by the Ford Foundation and ingested by RAC as Accessions 2019:186 and 2020:009.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of reports, grant summaries, and memos related to the Ford Foundation's Foreign Policy Task Force, national security issues in the United States, U.S. international relations, and human rights.
Foreign policy -- United States; National security -- United States; Human rights
- Ford Foundation Reports on Foreign Policy, 1983-2007; 1; 0.76 Cubic Feet 3 boxes (1 letter document box and 2 half letter document boxes)
  - Discussion Paper: International Affairs Program: Future Directions, Meeting of the Human Rights, Governance and International Affairs Committee, 1992 March (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Foundations with U.S. Foreign Policy/International Relations Programs, Sarah Ashton, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - A Safer America? Experts Respond to Congress and the Bush Administration, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Foreign Policy Task Force (FPTF), 2002-2005 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Foreign Policy Learning Circle, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Security After 9/11: Strategy Choices and Budget Tradeoffs: A Briefing Book, 2003 January (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Foreign Policy Task Force Documents, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Fundamental Questions about the Foreign Policy Task Force, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The U.S. Foreign Policy Portfolio, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Recommendations - Foreign Policy Task Force on Subcommittee on Constituency Building, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Foreign Policy Task Force Background Paper, 2003 January (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Foundations Funding U.S. Foreign Policy Program Memo, Sarah Ashton, 1994 February (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Discussion Paper - Foreign Policy and International Relations, For Discussion at the December 1988 Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1988 December (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Discussion Paper - U.S. Foreign Policy, For discussion at the meeting of the Trustees' Human Rights, Governance and International Affairs Committee, 1983 December 7 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Public Engagement in U.S. Foreign Policy After the Cold War, The Eighty-Third American Assembly, Arden House, Harriman, New York, 1993 June (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Human Rights Field Meeting, Antigua, Guatemala, Bonnie Jenkins, 2005 October 1-5 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Fiscal Year 2006 Grants of Bonnie Jenkins, 2005 December (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - The Voice of Veterans on Foreign Policy Report for the Ford Foundation, 2005 December (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Africa-China-U.S. Trilateral Dialogue Summary Report (Grant 10650736), undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Engaging Tomorrow: The Ford Foundation and Regional Security, Peace and Cooperation in South Asia, 50 Years of the Ford Foundation in India, Dr. Navnita Chadha Behera, 50th Anniversary Monograph Series, New Delhi, 2002 April (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - American Faith-Based Organizations and U.S. Foreign Policy: A Preliminary Mapping of Organizations and Issues, Jessica Lieberman, 2006 January 11 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Business Community Engagement in Foreign Affairs, Part I: Analysis of Existing Organizational Models, Presented to the Ford Foundation, 2005 August 29 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Appendix 8 through 17 (Grant Attachments?), 2006-2007 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Scope and Contents
    Appendix 8: Revised Process for "Putting P in PSJ"
    Appendix 9: Foreign Policy Learning Circle
    Appendix 10: Darfur Grants
    Appendix 11A: Darfur Interim Report
    Appendix 11B: Darfur Interim Report
    Appendix 12: Ford Involvement and Darfur Crisis
    Appendix 13: Portfoloio Summary of TCI
    Appendix 14: Memo to VP's Transnational Economic Justice
    Appendix 15: Request Letter for Learning Enhancement FUnds
    Appendix 16: Debrief of Design Team #2
    Appendix 17: Connect US
  - Report of the Study for the Ford Foundation on Policy and Program, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Survey of Programs on United States - China Relations and Security Issues, 2007 March (Box 3, Folder 25)